<Vocab id="5d4fd1e9-3692-4b68-9be4-fe0af96f2157" word="evolution" type="short" status="done">
  <Topics>
    <Topic id="0f6bec84-7965-4717-8b83-21192946653b" value="Science" />
  </Topics>
  <Professions>
    <Profession id="2f07befb-7e2b-4e4c-8ec3-c4a6b118826d" value="Biologist" />
    <Profession id="08c3c0b0-aa96-418e-93b4-4b894f114494" value="Paleontologist" />
    <Profession id="65149e82-0093-4536-bc06-6208733876b8" value="Educator" />
  </Professions>
  <Pronunciations>
    <Pronunciation id="f49f2dce-2675-4216-999c-6de28966b2c1" ipa="/ˌiː.vəˈluː.ʃən/" vi_ipa="i-vơ-lu-si-ơn">
      <Audios>
        <Audio type="male_normal" value="./male_normal.mp3" />
        <Audio type="male_slow" value="./male_slow.mp3" />
        <Audio type="female_normal" value="./female_normal.mp3" />
        <Audio type="female_slow" value="./female_slow.mp3" />
      </Audios>
      <Meanings>
        <Meaning id="0946faf6-041f-4637-91c1-ba3471d45a62" type="Noun">
          <Vi>quá trình tiến hóa</Vi>
          <En>The gradual development of something, especially from a simple to a more complex form; in biology, the process by which different kinds of living organisms are thought to have developed and diversified from earlier forms during the history of the earth.</En>
          <Example>Charles Darwin’s theory of evolution by natural selection revolutionized biology.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="28ba1754-1f9a-436f-a613-c02fe91bc8cf">
              <Vi>Giảng giải sự thay đổi dần dần của các loài sinh vật qua nhiều thế hệ.</Vi>
              <En>Explaining the gradual change in species over successive generations.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="3afba46c-1d1d-465f-8427-25d6f4a07af9">
              <Vi>Trong tranh luận về giáo dục khoa học, "evolution" thường đề cập đến thuyết tiến hóa.</Vi>
              <En>In science education debates, "evolution" often refers to the theory of evolution.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
        <Meaning id="5300c2f1-5808-4cc6-86d6-622a0caa0e66" type="Noun">
          <Vi>sự phát triển, tiến bộ (theo hướng phức tạp hơn, tốt hơn)</Vi>
          <En>The process of change in something over time, especially in a gradual and cumulative way, often implying improvement or increasing complexity.</En>
          <Example>The evolution of smartphones has transformed how we communicate and access information.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="00be98b3-5830-4996-a470-7b4a1dcf31d7">
              <Vi>Mô tả sự phát triển công nghệ qua các thế hệ sản phẩm.</Vi>
              <En>Describing how technology develops across successive product generations.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="70f5aa98-3415-45fe-b041-e861bd33758b">
              <Vi>Trong nghệ thuật, chỉ sự thay đổi phong cách qua các thời kỳ.</Vi>
              <En>In art, referring to stylistic changes across historical periods.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
      </Meanings>
    </Pronunciation>
  </Pronunciations>
</Vocab>