<Vocab id="044e166f-5d2b-4b9d-8084-0e83185541ac" word="omega" type="short" status="done">
  <Topics>
    <Topic id="0f6bec84-7965-4717-8b83-21192946653b" value="Science" />
    <Topic id="f3fd86a9-6e4e-47cd-b792-aad6917e0235" value="Mathematics" />
    <Topic id="7a9d003b-240a-4c7c-80fe-09c289b99b3a" value="Religion" />
  </Topics>
  <Professions>
    <Profession id="e2905533-6f6d-4e87-834d-097fd4d4f8a5" value="Physicist" />
    <Profession id="00fa1fe4-5cae-4551-9be7-3a587dffef6f" value="Mathematician" />
    <Profession id="c8c74904-1813-46ed-9195-00f2729a409a" value="Theologian" />
  </Professions>
  <Pronunciations>
    <Pronunciation id="184f83df-f316-406b-b4ce-75c7aa3b52d5" ipa="/ˈoʊ.mɪɡ.ə/" vi_ipa="ô-mê-ga">
      <Audios>
        <Audio type="male_normal" value="./male_normal.mp3" />
        <Audio type="male_slow" value="./male_slow.mp3" />
        <Audio type="female_normal" value="./female_normal.mp3" />
        <Audio type="female_slow" value="./female_slow.mp3" />
      </Audios>
      <Meanings>
        <Meaning id="b834ebd2-cb1f-4d8f-bccc-774b98b5cba9" type="Noun">
          <Vi>chữ omega (chữ cái cuối cùng trong bảng chữ cái Hy Lạp, tương đương với “o” trong tiếng Việt)</Vi>
          <En>the last letter of the Greek alphabet (Ω or ω), equivalent to the English “o” in sound</En>
          <Example>The symbol Ω is used in physics to represent electrical resistance.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="848d76ec-b7eb-47aa-9c8e-ad88a0c182d3">
              <Vi>Trong toán học và vật lý, omega thường được dùng để ký hiệu cho điện trở, tốc độ góc, hoặc số lượng hữu hạn lớn nhất trong lý thuyết tập hợp.</Vi>
              <En>In mathematics and physics, omega is commonly used to denote electrical resistance, angular velocity, or the largest finite ordinal in set theory.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="25de1baa-f2f2-48ff-afb0-99575411de84">
              <Vi>Trong Kitô giáo, omega tượng trưng cho sự kết thúc, thường đi kèm với alpha (bắt đầu) trong các biểu tượng thần học.</Vi>
              <En>In Christianity, omega symbolizes the end, often paired with alpha (the beginning) in theological symbolism.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
        <Meaning id="71ca6a9e-e844-40f7-aefa-48016c6a7680" type="Noun">
          <Vi>omega-3 (danh từ rút gọn), một loại axit béo thiết yếu quan trọng cho sức khỏe</Vi>
          <En>short for omega-3 fatty acid, an essential polyunsaturated fat important for health</En>
          <Example>Fish oil is a rich source of omega-3, which supports heart and brain health.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="61509ff1-3657-487b-9d0c-52cc2f31f06b">
              <Vi>Trong dinh dưỡng, omega-3 thường được nhắc đến trong các sản phẩm bổ sung và thực phẩm chức năng.</Vi>
              <En>In nutrition, omega-3 is frequently mentioned in supplements and functional foods.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
      </Meanings>
    </Pronunciation>
  </Pronunciations>
</Vocab>