<Vocab id="d69ed531-e462-4394-b67f-c06a9301d8ff" word="recall" type="short" status="done">
  <Topics>
    <Topic id="e2ab23d5-42b9-4d9a-8700-fc2bcd7e730a" value="Education" />
    <Topic id="52e30d7e-1450-4e76-a3a0-c745ac16ed27" value="Psychology" />
    <Topic id="085b2651-e3b7-438b-8ea4-750755ca7ae5" value="Technology" />
  </Topics>
  <Professions>
    <Profession id="130bc728-6b8d-489f-9fa3-9ac65578a282" value="Teacher" />
    <Profession id="b92a4351-4ec6-448a-beac-1c29fba7331c" value="Psychologist" />
    <Profession id="d732a0a7-04cc-4586-b0fd-70989e7387ba" value="Software Developer" />
  </Professions>
  <Pronunciations>
    <Pronunciation id="82d52f5a-8416-4b2f-8a8e-f14680b7edb0" ipa="/rɪˈkɔːl/" vi_ipa="ri-coul">
      <Audios>
        <Audio type="male_normal" value="" />
        <Audio type="male_slow" value="" />
        <Audio type="female_normal" value="" />
        <Audio type="female_slow" value="" />
      </Audios>
      <Meanings>
        <Meaning id="559d43d9-47ac-47a7-ad21-fd7aa15b8038" type="Verb">
          <Vi>nhớ lại, truy xuất (ký ức, thông tin)</Vi>
          <En>To bring back to mind or memory; to retrieve information from memory.</En>
          <Example>She struggled to recall the name of the restaurant where they had their first date.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="7d7d80c3-cfa9-4b59-bd56-b534040a6628">
              <Vi>Tình huống học sinh trả lời câu hỏi trong kỳ thi bằng cách nhớ lại kiến thức đã học.</Vi>
              <En>A student answers a test question by retrieving previously learned information from memory.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="e8a02301-237d-4d8c-ab42-e600530c50ac">
              <Vi>Tình huống một người nhớ lại chi tiết sự kiện đã xảy ra trong quá khứ sau khi được gợi ý.</Vi>
              <En>Someone remembers a specific detail of a past event after being prompted or reminded.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
        <Meaning id="d0dd0eda-452b-43f3-935d-f21f22ff0593" type="Verb">
          <Vi>hủy bỏ, thu hồi (quyết định, lệnh, sản phẩm)</Vi>
          <En>To officially cancel or revoke a decision, order, or product (e.g., due to error or safety concerns).</En>
          <Example>The company issued a recall of the defective car models after several accidents were reported.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="18f2df3e-fe51-456e-ae10-789b080822c7">
              <Vi>Tình huống nhà sản xuất thu hồi lô sản phẩm vì phát hiện lỗi nghiêm trọng.</Vi>
              <En>A manufacturer withdraws a batch of products from the market due to a serious safety defect.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="97132027-be96-4869-aad7-a87edd40045c">
              <Vi>Tình huống chính phủ thu hồi một đạo luật đã được thông qua nhưng vi phạm Hiến pháp.</Vi>
              <En>The government annuls a law that has been passed but is found to violate the Constitution.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
      </Meanings>
    </Pronunciation>
    <Pronunciation id="46d04de6-9f57-48a4-b113-a186ae253881" ipa="/ˈriː.kɔːl/" vi_ipa="ri-coul">
      <Audios>
        <Audio type="male_normal" value="" />
        <Audio type="male_slow" value="" />
        <Audio type="female_normal" value="" />
        <Audio type="female_slow" value="" />
      </Audios>
      <Meanings>
        <Meaning id="4a11e7b1-8ca8-4e7a-a3d3-1bbed3af8556" type="Noun">
          <Vi>sự nhớ lại, sự truy xuất ký ức</Vi>
          <En>The act of remembering or retrieving information from memory.</En>
          <Example>His recall of the conversation was remarkably accurate despite the passage of time.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="e6abbf56-dbbe-48b9-a7e7-11fa6083719d">
              <Vi>Tình huống một nhân chứng cung cấp chi tiết sự kiện trong phiên tòa dựa trên trí nhớ.</Vi>
              <En>A witness provides detailed accounts of an event in court based on their memory.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="d74330e5-16c9-4f05-bb08-f848c8d08e95">
              <Vi>Tình huống một ứng viên trả lời câu hỏi phỏng vấn bằng cách nhớ lại kinh nghiệm làm việc trước đây.</Vi>
              <En>A candidate answers interview questions by recalling previous work experiences.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
        <Meaning id="86ae9b73-7898-4640-8a75-f9fbb0a491fb" type="Noun">
          <Vi>sự thu hồi (sản phẩm, lệnh)</Vi>
          <En>The act of officially withdrawing a product, order, or decision, especially for safety or legal reasons.</En>
          <Example>The recall of the pharmaceutical batch prevented widespread health risks.</Example>
          <IsArchaic>false</IsArchaic>
          <Situations>
            <Situation id="9e66b211-789f-4532-8f4f-b12fe065cf98">
              <Vi>Tình huống người tiêu dùng nhận được thông báo về việc thu hồi thực phẩm bị nhiễm khuẩn.</Vi>
              <En>Consumers receive a notice about the recall of food products contaminated with bacteria.</En>
            </Situation>
            <Situation id="11973fbd-95db-4843-8ccd-b18549735a04">
              <Vi>Tình huống cơ quan quản lý yêu cầu thu hồi một loại thuốc sau khi phát hiện tác dụng phụ nghiêm trọng.</Vi>
              <En>A regulatory agency orders the recall of a drug after serious side effects are identified.</En>
            </Situation>
          </Situations>
        </Meaning>
      </Meanings>
    </Pronunciation>
  </Pronunciations>
</Vocab>